

Information Extraction · Natural Language Processing · Machine Learning

No.2, Southeast University Road, Jiangning District, Nanjing City, Jiangsu Province, 210089, P.R. China

 \square (+86) 159-5205-0556 | \blacksquare liubing_cs@seu.edu.cn

"All human misery stems from the indignation of one's own incompetence."

My Summary .

I am now a second year Ph.D. student at the School of Computer Science and Engineering in the Southeast University, China. My research interests mainly lie in Information Extraction, Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning.

Education

PH.D. Candidate in Computer Science and Technology

SCHOOL OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, SOUTHEAST UNIVERSITY, CHINA

• Advisor: Prof. Guilin Qi [gqi@seu.edu.cn]

M.E. in Transportation Planning and Management

SCHOOL OF TRANSPORTATION, SOUTHEAST UNIVERSITY, CHINA

• Advisor: Prof. Wei Wang [wangwei@seu.edu.cn]

B.S. in Information and Computing Science

SCHOOL OF MATHEMATICS, SOUTHEAST UNIVERSITY, CHINA

Nanjing, China

Mar. 2017 - PRESENT

Nanjing, China

Sep. 2014 - Dec. 2016

Nanjing, China

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

Research Experience

Key Technologies of Person Profiling and Positioning Analysis for Large-scale and **Multi-source Data**

A RESEARCH PROGRAM OF "NATURAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION OF CHINA"

Jan, 2018 - Present

Southeast University

· Duties: Researching Theories about Entity linking by combining entity mention and knowledge; Joint extraction of multiple properties and relations about person.

A Toolkit of Natural Language Processing

A COOPERATIVE RESEARCH PROGRAM WITH AN ENTERPRISE

Southeast University Oct, 2018 - Present

· Duties: Developing a toolkit for entity recognition, entity linking, relatioin extraction, event extraction and representation learning of knowledge base.

Technologies of Entity Relation Extraction Based on Deep Learning and Reasoning

Southeast University

A COOPERATIVE RESEARCH PROGRAM WITH AN ENTERPRISE

Nov, 2017 - Apr, 2018

• Duties: Researching Theories about relation extraction based on deep reinforcement learning and rules.

Coordination Mechanism and Coupling Theory of Multi Mode Public Transport Network

Southeast University

A RESEARCH PROGRAM OF "NATIONAL KEY BASIC RESEARCH PROGRAM OF CHINA"

Sep, 2015 - Sep, 2016

• Duties: Developing a software for graphic analysis of urban traffic network.

Theories and Key Technologies for Improving the Efficiency of Modern Urban

Southeast University

A RESEARCH PROGRAM OF "NATURAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION OF CHINA"

Multimodal Public Transportation System

Sep, 2014 - Sep, 2015

• Duties: Researching and implementing the traffic assignment algorithm.

Publications & Patents

Adversarial Discriminative Denoising for Distant Supervision Relation Extraction

AAAI 2019 (Under Review)

BING LIU, HUAN GAO, GUILIN QI*, SHANGFU DUAN, TIANXING WU, MENG WANG

Relation Extraction based on Reinforcement Learning and Reasoning (in Chinese)

2018 Patent

BING LIU, GUILIN QI

Adversarial Learning based Denoising Method for Distant Supervision Relation Extraction (in Chinese)

2018 Patent

BING LIU, GUILIN QI

Main Frame for Integrated Analysis of Comprehensive Transportation System (V1.0)

2016 Software

BING LIU, WEI WANG

• Chinese register No. 2016SR246196

Graphic Analysis System for Comprehensive Transportation System (V1.0)

2016 Software

BING LIU, WEI WANG

• Chinese register No. 2016SR245507

Graphic Analysis System for Highway Transportation System (V1.0)

2016 Software

BING LIU, WEI WANG

• Chinese register No. 2016SR246046

Honors & Awards

Apr. 2013 , Meritorious Winner on the International MCM	top 10%
May. 2012 , First Prize of Southeast University MCM	top 10%
Jun. 2014, The Ten Most Influential Graduates of Southeast University	10/3000
Jun. 2014, Outstanding Graduates of Southeast University	3/80
Oct. 2018 , "Chuangwei" Scholarship	2/90
May. 2012, "Subote" Scholarship	1/80
2010-2014, Several Scholarships for Excellence in Major Courses	top 5%

Skills____

Research Interests Information Extraction, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, Deep Learning,

Reinforcement Learning

Programming Languages Python, C/C++, Java, Javascript, Matlab, LaTeX, Html **Frameworks or Packages** Tensorflow, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Qt, Django

Mathematic Abilities Calculus, Advanced Algebra, Probability Theory, Statistics, Optimality Theory, Mathematical Modeling,

Functions of Complex Variables, Functions of Real Variables (some other math majors)

Language Skills English CET6